<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-03-05T21:43:48+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Chiiika’s Domain</title><subtitle>Clarissa is a IT student. This is a website where she posts her thoughts and experiments. Chika is her alias and lurks everywhere.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Clarissa’s Gaming intro</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/clarissa/2023/03/05/quarksgaming.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Clarissa’s Gaming intro" /><published>2023-03-05T19:20:00+08:00</published><updated>2023-03-05T19:20:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/clarissa/2023/03/05/quarksgaming</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/clarissa/2023/03/05/quarksgaming.html"><![CDATA[<p>I have been gaming from at least Primary 6 in primary school - so I can sorta say that I’ve played quite a few games and have a little bit of experience in gaming.</p>

<p><em>The genre I most like</em> - Space, Sandbox, Colony Sims, Rhythm Games</p>

<p><em>Some gaming skills</em> - Game server management, building ingame factories</p>

<p><em>Playing Style</em> - Support/Defensive/Reactive</p>

<p><em>Alias that I use</em> - Chika, Yvonne, Rinko - if you see accounts from these names they may be Clarissa’s testing accounts!</p>

<p><em>The most played game</em> - Minecraft logging at at least 2000+ hours - Minecraft is one of the first game I play.</p>

<p><em>Games that I still play a lot of</em></p>
<ul>
  <li>Minecraft</li>
  <li>Elite Dangerous</li>
  <li>No Man Sky</li>
  <li>Bandori</li>
  <li>Proseka</li>
  <li>Phigros</li>
  <li>Satisfactory</li>
</ul>

<p><em>Programming games that I like</em></p>
<ul>
  <li>Human Resource Machine - Super useful to anyone who intends to do programming or derivatives of!</li>
  <li>7 Billion Humans - Concurrent Programming</li>
  <li>Screeps</li>
  <li>Zachtronics games, including SpaceChem / Shenzhen I/O / Opus Magnum</li>
  <li>Baba is You</li>
  <li>Zach-like, Last Call BBS</li>
</ul>

<p><em>Rhythm games that I like</em></p>
<ul>
  <li>Rhythm Doctor</li>
  <li>Bandori &lt;- recently grinding Ringing Bloom on Piano, might do a writeup on it in the future about the current graduation events</li>
  <li>Proseka</li>
  <li>Phigros</li>
  <li>maimai/chuuni</li>
  <li>Just Shapes and Beats</li>
</ul>

<p><em>Colony sims that I like</em></p>
<ul>
  <li>Surviving Mars &lt;- you should buy the green planet expansion - it gives you so much hope.</li>
  <li>Oxygen Not Included</li>
</ul>

<p><em>4X games that I like</em></p>
<ul>
  <li>Stellaris</li>
</ul>

<p><em>Indie games that I like</em></p>
<ul>
  <li>FTL - Faster than Light &lt;- very good entry level roguelike</li>
  <li>Into the Breach</li>
  <li>Celeste, obviously</li>
</ul>

<p><em>Perspective/illusions Games that I like</em></p>
<ul>
  <li>Antichamber</li>
  <li>Superliminal</li>
  <li>Monument Valley (I&amp;II)</li>
</ul>

<p><em>some story games</em></p>
<ul>
  <li>INFRA</li>
  <li>Portal (1&amp;2)</li>
  <li>the Stanley Parable</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="clarissa" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I have been gaming from at least Primary 6 in primary school - so I can sorta say that I’ve played quite a few games and have a little bit of experience in gaming.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">www.chiiika.com resolving to Github Pages</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/thisblog/2023/03/05/switch.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="www.chiiika.com resolving to Github Pages" /><published>2023-03-05T06:57:00+08:00</published><updated>2023-03-05T06:57:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/thisblog/2023/03/05/switch</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/thisblog/2023/03/05/switch.html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>If only there is a self hosted Bear version.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Clarissa here. If you don’t know - this blog is maintained by a girl who has her own server infrastructure.</p>

<p>There is not a point to make - this is originally a space for me to write something - for writing down those items that, in the future may help me or any Minecraft server admins further down the road, as some sort of a logbook for me. Therefore - the website was designed only to be <em>enough</em> - without the bloat that is wordpress - without any payment stuff using Ghost - just me and my words and words that <em>might</em> be useful for the next traveller and the next sysadmin.</p>

<p>Thank you Annabelle for pointing out that the original Bear Blog is down somewhere in the past week - the option for custom domains and stuff have been removed on the free version of Bear. Although - even though the main point of the blog is to document words - at the end of the day I still wants my own blog on my own domain (on my own server if preferable).</p>

<p>Therefore - this Blog will be transferred onto a Jekyll page on Github Pages. Although - the words will remain the same.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="thisblog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[If only there is a self hosted Bear version.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">General Rules that can be Copied (!)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/minecrafting/admincraft/adminship/2022/10/20/genrules.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="General Rules that can be Copied (!)" /><published>2022-10-20T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2022-10-20T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/minecrafting/admincraft/adminship/2022/10/20/genrules</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/minecrafting/admincraft/adminship/2022/10/20/genrules.html"><![CDATA[<p>It has been no secret that people often needs to make rules for some venture; like Discord Servers; Minecraft Servers or chatrooms. Here is a sample list of rules to bootstrap your venture without falling into the pits of missed rules and a heck of a argument later on. Essential Rules are listed first in cardinal order; while non Essential Rules are listed in point form and can be adopted as wished.</p>

<p>(stuff) means fill the word suitable for you;
[stuff] means it can be adopted word for word;
//means comment</p>

<h1 id="chatrooms-including-discord">Chatrooms; including Discord</h1>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Do not be a jerk. Do not say, or do stuff that makes others uncomfortable. If asked to stop; Stop.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Do be kind and make others comfortable.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Do not spam, unless in authorized channels; especially spamming of pinging, private messaging or repeated harassment of any type against unwilling server members are forbidden.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Do not impersonate staff or other server members, nor post personal details of others.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Do not spew hate speech against others.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Do not advertise other than authorized.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Staff member’s decisions can be appealed once to the Founder; where the decision is Final. Listen and do as decided.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Do not break the TOS of the platform.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Do not scam other players.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Please inform the Staff about any grievances you find on platform.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>(language) is the primary method of communication on the server.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>You can be punished on violation of the aforementioned rule as decided by the Staffs.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>If any ambiguity arises, ask the staff - the Staff holds the final say.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<h3 id="if-nsfw-channels-existsif-it-does-not-exist-but-is-a-sfw-room">If NSFW channels exists/if it does not exist but is a SFW room</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Only post NSFW materials in our NSFW channels/Do not post NSFW materials. This is a (family or other applicable adjective) server.</li>
</ul>

<h1 id="minecraft-servers">Minecraft Servers</h1>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Do be civil, and don’t be a jerk.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>No hacking, cheating, or abuse of the server is allowed in any way, shape or form.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Do not spam [or try to bypass the chat filter //although implementing the chat filter is a bad idea (tm)], or send harmful links on the server.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Chatrooms rule applies here for the chat messaging function.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Do not build any kind of lag machines on the server, unless the server is Pay to Win. If the server is fully Pay to Win as defined by <a href="tab:https://docs.google.com/document/d/1Rd8vkKvpln6uhgO4XIUctWS5VkaxyZRc0h8Bb9GaxLI/edit">this document</a>, the licensing<sup id="fnref:licensing" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:licensing" class="footnote" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> for the entirety of the Ruleset is revoked since said usage is commercial.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>You may be banned as a result of violation of the rules.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<h2 id="general-survival-ruleset">General Survival Ruleset</h2>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Do not engage in nonconsensual PvP.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Do not steal, or generally griefing of other’s work.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<h2 id="general-creative-ruleset">General Creative Ruleset</h2>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Do not grief others.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Do not steal other’s work by plagiarism. Build your own work.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<h2 id="general-anarchy-philosophy">General Anarchy Philosophy</h2>

<blockquote>
  <p>This document will not touch into the philosophy, instead of actual rules for Anarchy Servers.</p>
</blockquote>

<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:licensing" role="doc-endnote">
      <p>This document is released as Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International. <a href="#fnref:licensing" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="minecrafting" /><category term="admincraft" /><category term="adminship" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It has been no secret that people often needs to make rules for some venture; like Discord Servers; Minecraft Servers or chatrooms. Here is a sample list of rules to bootstrap your venture without falling into the pits of missed rules and a heck of a argument later on. Essential Rules are listed first in cardinal order; while non Essential Rules are listed in point form and can be adopted as wished.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why Civilization, as a long server aim, is impossible</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/minecrafting/admincraft/coolname/2022/04/04/coolname-nociv.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why Civilization, as a long server aim, is impossible" /><published>2022-04-04T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2022-04-04T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/minecrafting/admincraft/coolname/2022/04/04/coolname-nociv</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/minecrafting/admincraft/coolname/2022/04/04/coolname-nociv.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/xmLLE1r.jpg" alt="Ingame screenshot" /></p>

<p>So, yeah: Coolname MC is a server that I mentored, and I regret not steering it clear of the civilization path.</p>

<h1 id="what-is-civilization-in-minecraft">What is Civilization in Minecraft</h1>

<p>A quick Youtube search will reveal that Civilization-like Minecraft endeavors started with a stunning 14M views of a video 7 months ago. In that video a Youtuber made some hundred of player login to a main Minecraft Server and they’re instructed to build a civilization according to the civilization they are assigned to. This, leads to struggles, politics, wars - all of which great content for a Youtuber.</p>

<p>Yet, apart from the video and entertaining value - civilization is a poisonous potato as to open a server. Here is why.</p>

<h1 id="a-poisonous-potato---deep-requirements">A poisonous potato - deep requirements</h1>

<p>Despite the reach of a stunning <em>14 million</em> views, civilization requires a heavy understanding of Minecraft to be played at. The random sorter is designed to group persons with higher knowledge and lower knowledge together using a principle known as Law of Large Numbers - if you have 100 people and they’re randomly sorted into 4 groups; chances are the abilities of each group is similar. Yet - this isn’t true at a server’s point of view; the sorting hat will change the scale so much in a sub-20 active server. Every specialist counts at a rate of 4 or 5 persons per civilization.</p>

<p>So - this is exactly what happened. Desert, civilization got a extreme lead that people from the other two civilization aren’t actively playing - they have no chance to win when the other civilization is overpowering them. This creates a vicious cycle as in said civilization will never raise itself up - thus reducing the attractiveness of the server to those in said civilization - which directly demotivates 3/4 of the server entrants and lead to a less than 25% retention rate.</p>

<h1 id="poisonous-potate-2-electric-boogaloo---login-times">Poisonous potate 2: electric boogaloo - login times</h1>

<p>Another facet of requirements of Civilization is the long attentive times required to achieve anything. As the defining video for Civilizations have established a strict server on-off schedule and more than 95% of the players are online - they do not have plugins like CoreProtect. Move that to a server aspect, and even Hypixel or the big names cannot make more than 5% of the total player online at any given moment - this will literally crash the server. Perpetual Civilization’s requirement is just too unsuitable for a general MC server.</p>

<h1 id="poisonous-potate-3-double-the-trouble---toxic-competitiveness">Poisonous potate 3: double the trouble - toxic competitiveness</h1>

<p>As players are sorted into 4 distinct tribes, tribalism will occur which directly reduces the cohesion factor of the Server itself - a brew for trouble. In the first Warzone as prescribed and monitored by Chika - The losing faction send <em>absolutely no one at all</em> as a direct result of point 1; and they are spawnkilled by the opposing faction (which leads to even lower retention rates if this is not ABSOLUTELY clear). After the obvious victory, the winning side proceeds to declare that 1/4 of people should not exist on the server - which again, reduces the retention rate by a tactical nuclear device.</p>

<h1 id="rebuttal---emergent-gameplay">Rebuttal - emergent gameplay</h1>

<p>It’s no secret that there are people who love to watch the world burn and will say that the above is just a direct result of emergent gameplay, which is gameplay objectives derived by the players, not the Administration or Minecraft itself. Yet, potential server hosts and administrator aspirant - mark my words - <strong>The wellbeing of the server at large, ALL of it’s players, including banned players is infinitely more valuable than a subset of it’s player</strong>. That’s why we need to enforce clear and equitable rules. That’s why we are in the Administration. If, in this case, emergent gameplay violates the above, squash that. Your players will thank you for that, and your server’s retention rate will not suffer the equivalent of a tactical nuclear device.</p>

<h1 id="words-to-coolname-mc">Words to CoolName MC</h1>

<p>Chika is sending this Essay to the Administration. I suggest that we should dissolve the current Objective, and build from scratch. That tactical nuke has dropped, but we still do have that Minecraft itch. Redo it, and make a better survival program.</p>

<p><em>Chika off.</em></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="minecrafting" /><category term="admincraft" /><category term="coolname" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Minecraft Trading Place Haruka - Day 3</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/minecrafting/2022/04/02/mtpharuka3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Minecraft Trading Place Haruka - Day 3" /><published>2022-04-02T12:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2022-04-02T12:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/minecrafting/2022/04/02/mtpharuka3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/minecrafting/2022/04/02/mtpharuka3.html"><![CDATA[<p>While working on the Nether Part of things, Chika found a strange interaction: The Essentials plugin was buying cactus at a rate of $10/block, which is ludicrous.</p>

<h2 id="big-cactus-farm">Big Cactus Farm</h2>

<p>So the design for cactus farm is extremely simple: cactus cactuses, and that cactus will get broken by fences up 1 block and sideways 1 block (this is important), therefore dropping cactus. One block of cactus will get us 2.3 cactus ($23) per hour, so: if we make 4347 cactus plant that cactuses we will get $100k/h, which is a acceptable rate for getting a good 20<em>20</em>15 plot in the Main World.</p>

<h2 id="how-do-we-get-4347-cactus-plant-that-cactuses">How do we get 4347 cactus plant that cactuses</h2>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>3rt(4347) ~ 16.32
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>It’s awfully close to 16, therefore Chika does so:</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>4347 = 16 x 16 x ?
? ~ 16.9 \= 17
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Therefore Chika need 16 rows and 16 columns of 17 level of cactus that cactuses.</p>

<h2 id="shopping-list">Shopping List:</h2>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>4352 cactuses (68s0)
4352 sand (68s0)
~3k wood logs (46s56)
~20k slabs (312s32)
...
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>I immediately noted that this is a extreme investment so I’m going to make a 3 layered 10*10 test of a cactus farm first.</p>

<h2 id="revised-shopping-list---again-from-shulkercraft">Revised Shopping List - again from Shulkercraft</h2>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>1k slab
800 glass
300 cactus
300 sand
270 fence
120 gates
7 hopper
10 chest
some water
some temp blks
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>It’s <em>13</em> hours till this point.</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>y-10 mine
 |- coal
 |- iron &amp; diamonds
 | |- basic gear
 | \- enchanting (prerequisite 1/2)
 \- redstone, stone
  \- different kinds of farms
exploration
 \- cows
   \- enchanting (prerequistite 2/2)
     \- advanced gear
cactus farm, autonomous
 |- selling cactus
 \- server cash (1x cactus = $10)
* slime farm, autonomous
 |- * cobblestone farm, autonomous
 | \- * selling stone related blocks
 \- * selling slime
</code></pre></div></div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="minecrafting" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[While working on the Nether Part of things, Chika found a strange interaction: The Essentials plugin was buying cactus at a rate of $10/block, which is ludicrous.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Minecraft Trading Place Haruka - Day 2b</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/minecrafting/2022/04/01/mtpharuka2b.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Minecraft Trading Place Haruka - Day 2b" /><published>2022-04-01T12:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2022-04-01T12:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/minecrafting/2022/04/01/mtpharuka2b</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/minecrafting/2022/04/01/mtpharuka2b.html"><![CDATA[<p>Chika here again, worked out the Nether.</p>

<h2 id="successful-containment-of-a-blaze-spawner">Successful Containment of a Blaze Spawner</h2>

<p>According to instructions on this video - <a href="tab:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=q7mGXe5dCHA">Tutorial by ShulkerCraft</a> - I built the Containment Structure around that Blaze Spawner another player told me the coordinates to, and built the Blaze Semiautonomous Farm.</p>

<p>I have made only one change to the tutorial - to <em>not</em> do the vines. It has been successfully cross-tested on other servers that project KIRAMEKI have presence in, and the blazes (or you) loves to break the vines anyway, and having vines do not actually add too much to the production of the Farm; so I removed the vines.</p>

<p>Chika’s target is to now get some slime, fill up my 13/1 bookshelf, get one or two more farms, and wait for the regulations to relax (or dig obsidian for monies) to build the shop proper.</p>

<p>I spent 10 hours to this point.</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>y-10 mine
 |- coal
 |- iron &amp; diamonds
 | |- basic gear
 | \- enchanting (prerequisite 1/2)
 \- redstone, stone
  \- different kinds of farms
exploration
 \- cows
   \- enchanting (prerequistite 2/2)
     \- advanced gear
blaze farm, semiautonomous
 \- selling mass brew
* slime farm, autonomous
 |- * cobblestone farm, autonomous
 | \- * selling stone related blocks
 \- * selling slime
</code></pre></div></div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="minecrafting" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chika here again, worked out the Nether.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Minecraft Trading Place Haruka - Day 2a</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/minecrafting/2022/03/31/mtpharuka2a.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Minecraft Trading Place Haruka - Day 2a" /><published>2022-03-31T12:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2022-03-31T12:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/minecrafting/2022/03/31/mtpharuka2a</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/minecrafting/2022/03/31/mtpharuka2a.html"><![CDATA[<p>Chika here again, spending 2 hours to clean the mess of yesterday.</p>

<p><strong>Day 2a: Failed Nether Expedition, jumping for slimes</strong></p>

<p>From the information given by the Administration, TNT duping for farm is prohibited in the main world, but is allowed in the Resource World. Therefore, all the Autonomous Farms must be done in the Resource World.</p>

<p>On the topic of brewing, Chika unsuccessfully went to the Nether and died numerous times. /tpr is a good thing, but Chika needs that Swamp biome in order to make the slime farm, which is the prerequisite to many types of farm.</p>

<p>I spent 5 hours to this point.</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>y-10 mine
 |- coal
 |- iron &amp; diamonds
 | |- basic gear
 | \- enchanting (prerequisite 1/2)
 \- redstone, stone
  \- different kinds of farms
exploration
 \- cows
   \- enchanting (prerequistite 2/2)
     \- advanced gear
* slime farm, autonomous
 |- * cobblestone farm, autonomous
 | \- * selling stone related blocks
 \- * selling slime
</code></pre></div></div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="minecrafting" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chika here again, spending 2 hours to clean the mess of yesterday.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Minecraft Trading Place Haruka - Day 1</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/minecrafting/2022/03/31/mtpharuka1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Minecraft Trading Place Haruka - Day 1" /><published>2022-03-31T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2022-03-31T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/minecrafting/2022/03/31/mtpharuka1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/minecrafting/2022/03/31/mtpharuka1.html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>I cannot be a VTuber, so I’ll see what my expertise can do!</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Chika here. This will be a multipart series in documenting my adventures in a certain Minecraft Server, where I attempt to set up a ton of shops to outdo the local server admin based shops &amp; make myself rich as a side effect.</p>

<p><strong>Kirameki Corp Haruka Division</strong> is therefore established.</p>

<h1 id="how-to-outdo-a-server">How to “outdo” a server</h1>

<ul>
  <li>Minecraft Experience</li>
  <li>Familarity with the almighty Google</li>
  <li>Building Skills</li>
  <li>Talking Skills</li>
  <li>Time to spend</li>
  <li>(preferably) new Administration &amp; new server, mostly with hobbyist</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="day-1-where-i-mine-to-level-10-and-get-myself-a-pair-of-cow">Day 1; where I mine to level 10, and get myself a pair of cow</h2>

<p>As I have limited time to do things in comparison to the bigger server and their total time spent, precise action are required. Setting up base in a secluded area, I quickly setted home and dug to level 10. Anything that expedite this progress is great, including a plugin that let me fell a tree on the base. I settled for the long mining journey for basic gear, using stone pickaxes as disposable tools as to branch mine and made a diamond pickaxe for the rare minerals, where I encountered much in the Resource Server. Most Resource Server reset very soon, for example one Server I mentored resets their Resource Server twice a week(!), yet this server only reset every 6 months, so it’s pretty safe to make even full farms here instead of in the main world, where mobs seems to be unable to spawn for a reason.</p>

<p>Branch Mining for a hour and I already have enough for basic unenchanted gear (and I made 2 sets, one was lost on a unlucky random teleport <em>onto a creeper</em> and another one was made, which <em>further</em> illustrates why branch mining is good despite Administration’s push for adventure); even their random dangerous weather plugin actually did the counter effect and pushed for people to camp up - a lesson on paradoxical effects for any aspiring server owner.</p>

<p>I also used random teleport to get myself leather in order to make enchanting tables, and made 3 bookshelves out of the 15 needed for a full table. I also captured 2 cows using this and used wheat from the public farm to save time.</p>

<p>The above costed 3 hours, and I logged out for theorycrafting. As the hardware of the server was not good, the Administration implemented a 5 living things per chunk rule, which is hard on farms - another issue was the extreme cost of the claims in the Main World, where I set the shops in. Yet, even with the longer reset period, Resource World <em>don’t</em> offer any type of protection. There are farms that must be built in the Resource World, like Manual Blaze Farms -</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>(Hereafter I’ll divide farms into two types - Autonomous Farms, as in Autonomous Cobblestone Farms, which require only chunk loading by player, and Manual Farms, as in Manual Blaze Farms, which do require player input. Another distinction to be made is AFK Farms, as in you can get a macro up and do other stuff; compared with Active Input Farms, where you must be in the game and actively click.)</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I’ll need to decide to place what farms at which server, as well as which /home to assign it to - since I can only make 3 homes in the Resource World. If I use only 2, I can additionally get a bonus to quickly get back to the Main World.</p>

<p>I’ll sign off here - this took me 3 hours up to this point.</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>y-10 mine
 |- coal
 |- iron &amp; diamonds
 | |- basic gear
 | \- enchanting (prerequisite 1/2)
 \- redstone, stone
  \- different kinds of farms
exploration
 \- cows
   \- enchanting (prerequistite 2/2)
     \- advanced gear
</code></pre></div></div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="minecrafting" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I cannot be a VTuber, so I’ll see what my expertise can do!]]></summary></entry></feed>